Come back to order for today's date.
Second, I don't even miss tortillas.
Miss tortillas.
Say the blessing for us.
Our most righteous and Heavenly Father, we come before you Lord.
We thank you so much for the avenue of prayer.
We thank you for your grace and your mercy.
And we thank you for your word and for Jesus Christ.
We ask that you bless this meeting Lord,
that the decisions that will be made will not go against you will.
And we know that your providence works Lord in ways that we don't understand,
but we know that you're in the background Lord, especially with the government.
And we ask that you be with us to make decisions that will help us be at peace with each other.
And that will be for the good will of this community and the city and those who live in it.
We thank you so much for everything, Lord.
Thank you for this opportunity of prayer again.
We ask that you be with the leaders of our city.
And in Jesus name we ask we pray.
Amen.
Thank you.
That would you like to hear this in the front or join me?
I'd like to hear this through the flag of the United States of America.
And to the Republic for which it stands.
One nation, the other God.
Individual with liberty and justice for all.
I don't remember for it.
It's public input and unscheduled personal appearances.
Anyone in the audience, it wishes to address the council or any of the agenda.
There being none.
I had them excuse me.
I had them five as a consent agenda.
Staff is recommending item six and seven for the consent agenda.
Do we have a motion?
Most of you are prudent.
Second, roll call, please.
Members, before you do, I should just point out that there is a transposition of numbers on item six.
Okay.
Senator claims it's five hundred and six thousand.
Whereas if you look at the actual list of the claims, the numbers should be five hundred and sixty.
But since that is all part of the agenda, I don't see that there is a particular problem with
proceeding with this.
Okay.
Thank you.
What we should do is, probably just pull a month.
This is only two of them.
Pull them out and pull them out and pull them separately with the correction.
I think that would be the best thing to do in that way to the record.
So then item six is claims in the amount of five hundred and sixty thousand eighty five sixty eight.
Do we have a motion to approve the claims amount?
Motion to approve.
And a second.
Roll call.
Johnson.
All right.
Question.
Item seven is a minutes from July 19.
Do we have a this year?
Do we have a motion to approve the minutes?
Motion to approve.
And a second.
So roll call.
Question.
All right.
Johnson.
Thank you for your diligence. Good start, Ben.
Item A is new business in any new business.
Dean, if you'd like to do a staff report either now or under the following item.
I wouldn't do it on the next item.
Okay. There's no new business in.
We'll move on to staff reports.
Go ahead.
As I had indicated to you and Tyler Klein is going to come on up and do this.
We've had a number of power out of just in the southwest part of Tim.
I think he'd been contacted by some of our customers about this.
It's certainly nothing that we're very happy about.
But you see our line crew back here and they are working very hard to try to resolve these problems.
But we thought it might be better just for you and also just for the record to give an update about what's happening and what we're trying to do to deal with this.
So Tyler, at that point, I'm going to turn it over to you.
Yes, sir.
We've started all off at the end of June.
We have this relays in our subsation and our slides are 351 that controls feeder 19,
which is what feeds the southwest.
It was damaged by lightning.
I mean, required replacements.
So we had to tie some feeders together until we got a new replacement relay.
We put the new relay in.
This really, like it says, controls the breaker operation and opening closing on the subsation.
So it's what closes.
It's like a house but in a lot of order of scale.
This second time we had an outage, which was the second week in July.
We replaced the lightning arrester.
They're back there around 17th, southwest.
And then the third time we went out and replaced some insulators along.
That's a street right there.
Kind of down from there to kicks processing.
There were some insulators that we thought were iffy.
So we replaced those.
And then I'll let you really talk about this.
Yeah.
We also, in doing that, we placed some line cheeses in a couple different locations.
So we could isolate any other problems.
We'd have a couple different areas.
When we did that, we ended up blowing a couple fuses feeding out towards
Eminem.
And we found that this right here, this insulated.
We go to that next slide also.
You can see where it's tracked down the pole.
There.
You see that burnt mark in that in it.
Not that feeder happens.
Didn't knock out the feeder.
It just knocked out part of that feeder at that point.
So that was the last outage that we had.
Except for.
It's done.
Sunday morning.
And we had a go to that next slide.
We had a fire in our substation on that same feeder.
It was unrelated to all these other problems we've had.
Go ahead in the next one.
And this is right behind that panel there.
You can see up there on top, perhaps, lighting the resters that are blown.
And it caused to go face to face down there.
We also determined this this afternoon that that cable's bad from there to
the rise there about 300.
We're on a 500 conductor there that we had to replace.
Coming up.
So.
Go back for just a minute.
You mentioned putting some line blikers.
If you don't use it.
Line fuses.
Yeah, we'd find that a little.
A few is of course.
It's just a one time off.
operation. And at there at the paragraphs, just to isolate what was going on to make sure
what we had, what we had, we put some fuses there, that away if the fault is past that
fuse, it blows it there. That away, it wouldn't take out the hole feeder back to that
relay. If those aren't there, the breaker sees the relay, the relay sees the fault, interlobe
in the breaker and shut off the hole feeder after three times. So we put them in there,
back fed, another part, off another spot, so that we can kind of isolate if we had any more
problems because we kept having issues and it seemed to be on B-phase a lot. And we did
find all these other problems and we just wanted to make sure that we knew which areas.
So is that a preventive measure or a diagnostic measure? That was diagnostic.
Okay. We use that to do that, to find this last incident.
And besides these specifics, Tyler, what in general are you guys doing?
That's the last slide that we have.
Some different things we've done to improve service. We've started doing monthly
subsations inspections on David Rantrie, helped to set up a program on our iPad, the guys go out
and check out three of our substations and go through a checklist. We've also began working
with GRDA and inspecting the subsations and transformers. I mean, we've had all of the
intensity this year. This is the first time since, I believe they said, late 90 or like
like 19 and 90s, early 2000s, it's just been done. So we took each one of them out of service,
had them tested, had them all tested. And we found a net bushing on the one at Rockdale. And
so we replaced that.
It's supposed to be done every five years. Yes, sir.
So.
We also were doing that. You've seen that substation there. We took all those panels off of that
and inspected all that at that time. We, lightning clusters on the transformers. We tested
all those. So I mean, we just had all that off of there. This is, we did quite a bit of
threatening it to this point to keep this from happening.
One of the calls, and I don't remember if there's a call, I got our conversation that you and I had suggested
that GRDA was having problems out in the county. And that was contributing to our problems. I don't
know if that was accurate or not. It was.
Yeah, that was Saturday. If you're talking about Saturday morning, Saturday morning, they actually
had GRDA actually blinked us and shut off two of our substation transformers and blink for about
10 seconds, about half the town. Probably it's all a blink.
That's what you're going to cross your question.
And what caused that do we know?
I do not know. They contacted us right after it happened. And asked us if all of our substations were good.
And we had the guys go out to the substations and check all the relays and all the breakers
at that time and everything checked out good. So it wasn't on us at all. I did not get a report back.
Yeah.
What did they found?
Okay.
A couple of other things that we've done.
We've placed two of the four breakers in substation one, which is the one that we're talking about.
And then we've also, since we recently brought Oston on board, we developed a seven year plan.
And then we, you know, the last meeting that hired Dan Jackson to do the right studies.
So, we're working with Oston to look over our seven year plans.
See if they have some changes and then also have Dan work with us on, you know, possible funding for our seven year plan.
Okay. So, which includes a lot of work on our substation.
Well, I think you'll remember even in our budget we had.
We had funding for a small amount of what we probably will have about a 1.4 million.
Or is that even a little too high?
That was water as well.
Yeah. So, trying to get a hold of that and have a capital plan and a funding plan.
So we can get out and do it in one fell swoop or at least in sections rather than just one thing at a time.
Which is what we're dealing with right now.
And so, it's most of this Tyler you think just do the third maintenance or they're okay.
So it's not what it is the fact that it's real hot.
That probably adds to it. I mean, just third maintenance and then you're pushing everything to you.
You're the expert in the height.
It's hot out there.
It's a total of all the equipment.
Anything else to do?
You just wanted to bring you in the public up to speed on what we're dealing with right now.
Not only with what we're dealing with immediately, but also that we're putting together a plan to deal with that in a kind of a whole basis.
Which is something that I've kind of cast Tyler in the electric crib do.
And they're coming through doing a great job right now.
You know, like I said, on a hot day when the power goes out or a cold day or a storm or anything like that.
Those are the people that are out there and we're safe at home.
So I do appreciate it.
All right. Thanks guys.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
I don't care.
Trust your community announcement.
Any announcements?
Have nothing.
No.
And I am 11 is motion to adjourn.
I'll make that motion.
Have a second.
Roll call please.
So.
Hi.
Bye.
All right.
Okay.
We're done.